We learned in our class something called well we call it the pat maneuver a LAPD officer Pat Bailey one our mentors thought us how to do this and we share this with parents because we found this the easiest way to install the seat.
So the first thing Pat thought use was to move th front seat all the way forward and get it out of the way.
And doing this could be a little harder in smaller vehicle but it still could be done.
The second thing we want to do is to make sure that there is nothing on the floor so when we get in here cause we are going to have to stand here so you want to have the floors empty.
Okay third thing is now you are going to climb in to the seat.
Get in.
Okay we have already run this through the belt path convertibles has two belt paths on of them is a rear facing belt path right here when it is in this position.
The forward facing belt path is right here so if the seat was turned around facing this way you would then use this belt path.
But since we are facing when you run the lap shoulder belt through here and the seat still moves around and it is still loose.
You can also notice because there is leather in this vehicle that we use a piece of non sticky material to help keep it from sliding around.
We have also because of the seat lopes in the vehicle using a pool noodle to adjust for angle.
The most important part is in installing a infant or parenting me a convertible seat is to make sure you have a 45 degree angle for a infant that does not have full head control or neck control.
If it is a child that has head control the angle does not need to be quiet 45 in could be a little more steep.
But you never ever would want it in a 90 like this.
So what Andrea and Pat though us to do would be to use your body to weight the sit I can reach down here and pull through this way like this and then I can rock the sit like this when I'm pulling in order to get it tight.
I have also Dan have switched the belt we need a locking magnetism and Dan is pulling the belt and we are rocking the sit side to side.
Then it feeds up in the magnetism the belt is locked and when you try to move the sit you always check your sit for installation at the belt path and when you try to move it side to side it is not moving and that is the proper way to install.
So the easies way to do this is with our pat maneuver by climbing up in the sit and rocking it and getting it nice and tight.